# 山东·日照
Rizhao. Shandong
# 大锅全羊
Huge pot of lamb soup
# 现在是不到11点 她们都在忙碌着切羊肉
It’s less than 11 am now, they are busy to cutting lamb
# 羊肉呢 要把肥的和瘦的分开来
They are splitting fatty and fatless lamb apart
# 你看 那个肥的都会被她们剔掉
you see, they take fatty lamb away
# 剩的羊肉就是瘦的多 肥的少
More fatless and less fatty in rest of lamb
# 看这羊肉切的是不是很带劲
See how they cut the lamb?
# 大姐 这边早上几点开门
Anut, what time is it open in the morning?
# 6点 6点就开始喝羊肉汤了
Around six o’clock
# 就喝羊肉汤了
# 老板3点就开始熬汤
The restaurant owner start cooking soup at 3 am
# 你看 这边的羊肉切的都是很大块的
You see, they cut lamb into large pieces
# 哇 这个羊骨头直接从肉上掰了下来
Wow, meat is easy to off the bone
# 这边是一个大棚 可能来的比较早
# 没有很多人在这边吃
# 早上来吃的大部分人还是在室内吃的
# 没想到今天天气这么热
# 好像只有我穿的比较厚
# 这个就是吃羊汤配的主食-大饼
# 这边还有韭菜花和咸菜
# 都是可以免费加的
# 我后面就是正在炖的羊 全羊
# 里面能够明显看到的是羊肉还有羊油
# 这冒的大泡 看起来就特别香
# 师傅 他们说羊蝎子11点之前有时候就会被抢光
# 对
# 羊蝎子多少钱
How much lamb spine is?
# 3块一个
3 yuan for each
# 那确实是很实惠
That’s really good price
# 这个好吃
This is delicious
# 你吃个吧
Do you want one?
# 现在不吃
Not yet
# 还没到饭点
It’s not time to eat
# 我要一个20的羊汤 再要一个羊骨髓
I want a 20 yuan lamb soup and a lamb bone marrow
# 哦（还没有点饼）
Oh(forget to order a
# 哪有羊骨髓
We don’t have lamb bone marrow
# 不是那个 羊蝎子
Not that one, I mean lamb spine
# 羊蝎子
Lamb spine
# 付了3块钱 买的是羊蝎子
Paid 3 yuan for a lamb spine
# 再加一个大饼 忘了
And a flatbread
# 你要6碗是吧
You want six bowls of lamb soup right?
# 调料在你后面 是吧 6碗 120元
Condiments are behind you, 120 yuan for six bowls of lamb soup
# 少一个怎么
Why there are only 5 bowls of soup
# 二四六 少一碗
Two,four,six, less one bowl of soup
# 不着急
Not in rush
# 现在开始上人了
Now costumers are coming
# 还没开始
Not yet
# 再给你加两片瘦肉
I will add two more lean meat for you
# 好 谢谢
Okay, thank you
# 多给你点 尝尝
I will give you more meat, try it
# 多吃点 你长那么瘦
Eat more meat, look how think you are
# 现在等着加汤了
Now we are waiting for them to add soup
# 自己舀吗
By your own?
# 好 谢谢
Okay, thank you
# 拿着大饼走吧
Let’s take flatbread and find our seat
# 看我们的羊汤 羊蝎子还有大饼都上桌了
Look, our lamb soup and lamb spine and flatbread are on table
# 大姐觉得我有点瘦
Aunt think I’m thin
# 所以 多给我加了几块瘦肉
So she add more lean meat for me
# 还有呢 就是 我要了一块羊蝎子
And I order a lamb spine
# 实际上 还多让了几块
They give me more than what I ordered
# 在此非常感谢他们
So thanks for them
# 这边基础的羊汤是15块钱
Basic soup is 15 yuan
# 如果说 想要多吃肉的话 可以自己再加钱
Pay more money to get more meat
# 像我呢 就是 要了一碗20块钱的
I order 20 yuan bowl of soup
# 要完肉之后
After you order meat
# 师傅会先把肉放在漏勺里
Shifu will put meat in a colander
# 然后用滚烫的羊汤来涮几下 冲几下
And boiled it with hot lamb soup
# 最后呢 就是再放上羊汤
Add lamb soup at the end
# 看样子 真的是觉得特别香
Looks very delicious
# 羊汤是没有味道的
Original Lamb soup are insipid taste
# 也没有膻味
And no tainted taste
# 我们需要自己加盐 加胡椒粉
We need to add salt and pepper by our own
# 肉就是 瘦的多 肥的少
There are less fatty and more lean meat
# 因为把肥的剔掉了嘛
Because they take off fatty
# 羊肉切的特别大块
They cut lamb meat into big pieces
# 好香啊
Smells so fragment
# 吃羊汤 配大饼
Eat lamb soup with flatbread
# 一口汤 一口肉加口饼
A bite of soup with a bite of flatbread
# 吃起来特别满足
Feels good
# 羊蝎子的肉 一吸溜就掉下来了
Meat of lamb spine is easy to take off the bone
# 五香味很足
With rich wuxiang(five spiced) flavor
# 大姐 我问几个问题
Big sis, I want ask you some questions
# 咱们原来在哪边干的
Where the restaurant open before
# 以前 我以前赶大集卖羊肉汤
I sale lamb soup at farmer market before
# 就农村那5天一个的大集
Farmer market which open every five days
# 对 日照大集上的羊汤是很出名的
Yeah, lamb soup in Rizhao farmer market are famous
# 顾客喜欢吃 他们说着玩 不是很出名
Our customers like it, they just saying it, not very famous
# 比咱优秀的有的是
We are not the best
# 什么时候到这边开的店
When you open the restaurant here?
# 三四年了可能是
About 3 or 4 years
# 这边一天最多能卖多少羊
How many lamb are sale every day?
# 以前一天 以前吧
We used sale
# 是能卖四五只 五六只
Four or five, five or six
# 现在吧 由于这个疫情反正卖的稍微少一点
But now we sale less due to the epidemic
# 这个羊肉一定要切成这种大块大片的吗
Do you have to cut lamb into big pieces or slices?
# 反正随意切 有时候切片 有时候切块
It depend, we sliced or cut into pieces
# 没有什么很要求的
Not necessary
# 现在我们在东夷小镇
Now we are at Dongyi down
# 关 注
雪 鱼 探 店